<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forensicwheels - Tag - Forensic wheels</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/forensicwheels/index.html</link>
    <description></description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:19:17 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/forensicwheels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/about/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 16:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/about/index.html</guid>
      <description>Hi! I’m Dirk, a security engineer with a passion for Skateboarding and Forensics. By day, I help my Company safeguard their networks and systems from the ever-evolving threats in the cybersecurity landscape.&#xA;But when the sun goes down, my true self emerges. Skateboarding is not just my hobby - it’s my passion, my center, and my identity. For me, Skatelife is more than just lifestyle; it’s a way of life that embodies creativity, freedom, and community and Family. I’ve been skating for years, and I still get that same feel every time I’m on my board.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenBSD and Zen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/openbsdzen/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 16:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/openbsdzen/index.html</guid>
      <description>About Simplicity and Clarity Attention to Detail The Power of Consistency The Beauty of Imperfection About As someone who is passionate about security and has an interest in Unix operating systems, OpenBSD particularly captivates due to its dedication to security, stability, and simplicity. In comparison to other OSes, what sets OpenBSD apart? And how do these principles align with my journey through Zen meditation?&#xA;At first glance, OpenBSD and Zen may appear to be vastly disparate concepts - one being a potent operating system, while the other is a spiritual practice originating from ancient China. However, as I delved deeper into both realms, I uncovered some fascinating similarities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SANS FOR608</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sans_for608/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 13:19:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sans_for608/index.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Threat hunting and Response (FOR608) Introduction Brief overview of forensic analysis and its application Course Overview Proactive Detection and Response (608.1) Scaling Response and Analysis (608.2) Modern Attacks against Windows and Linux DFIR (608.3) Analyzing macOS and Docker Containers (608.4) Cloud Attacks and Response (608.5) Capstone: Enterprise-Class IR Challenge Key Takeaways Summary of key concepts and skills learned during the course learning outcomes and their application in real-world scenarios Conclusion and Recommendations Summary of overall effectiveness of the SANS Forensics course for608 Recommendations for future students looking to learn forensic analysis skills Enterprise Threat hunting and Response (FOR608) Course description from SANS 1 :</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HoneyHTTPD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/honeyhttpd/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/honeyhttpd/index.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction Brief overview of the use case: ingesting web data into Elasticsearch with HoneyPot HTTPD Setting up HoneyPot HTTPD for Web Data Ingestion Containerizing the application to run inside docker Ingesting Web Data into Elasticsearch with HoneyPot HTTPD Explanation of how to use the honeyhttpd command-line tool to ingest web data into Elasticsearch Example of how to configure the honeyhttpd output to match your desired Elasticsearch index structure Benefits and Use Cases Discussion of the benefits of using HoneyPot HTTPD for ingesting web data into Elasticsearch (e.g., improved threat detection, enhanced visibility) Real-world examples of use cases where this setup can be particularly effective (e.g., logging web traffic, monitoring online activity) Conclusion Recap of key points about using HoneyPot HTTPD to ingest web data into Elasticsearch*** Final thoughts on the value of this setup for your organization’s threat hunting or security operations. I. Introduction Brief overview of the use case: ingesting web data into Elasticsearch with HoneyPot HTTPD I recently set out to ingest web traffic data into our SIEM solution, which requires data to be ingested in a specific format. After researching various options, I sought an easy-to-use solution that could integrate with our existing Elasticsearch setup. One tool that caught my attention was HoneyPot HTTPD.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>