<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forensicwheels - Tag - Forensic wheels</title>
    <link>http://localhost:44975/tags/forensicwheels/index.html</link>
    <description></description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 10:19:19 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:44975/tags/forensicwheels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:44975/about/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 16:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:44975/about/index.html</guid>
      <description>Short intro about myself</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenBSD and Zen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:44975/posts/openbsdzen/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 12:48:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:44975/posts/openbsdzen/index.html</guid>
      <description>About As someone who is passionate about security and has an interest in Unix operating systems, OpenBSD particularly captivates due to its dedication to security, stability, and simplicity. In comparison to other OSes, what sets OpenBSD apart? And how do these principles align with my journey through Zen meditation?&#xA;At first glance, OpenBSD and Zen may appear to be vastly disparate concepts - one being a potent operating system, while the other is a spiritual practice originating from ancient China. However, as I delved deeper into both realms, I uncovered some fascinating similarities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just a shell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:44975/justashell/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 10:19:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:44975/justashell/index.html</guid>
      <description>What Burned Me Built Me I used to believe that the place I worked for meant something. That our mission was shared. That our values were real. That if you showed up with honesty, effort, and a willingness to carry more than your share — you’d be met with respect. Or at least, fairness.&#xA;I was wrong.&#xA;Disappointment What hurts isn’t the exit itself. What hurts is realizing that the foundation I stood on was never really there at all. That the culture I believed in — the one I helped build — was, in the end, just an image.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>