<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forensicwheels - Tag - Forensic wheels</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/forensicwheels/index.html</link>
    <description></description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:21:34 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/forensicwheels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 16:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/index.html</guid>
      <description>Short intro about myself</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Yellow Shards in Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/yellowshardsinelastic/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/yellowshardsinelastic/index.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction If you’re running Elasticsearch on a single node — like a Raspberry Pi or small lab setup like I am — you might notice some indices appear with a yellow health status.&#xA;This show article explains what that means and how to fix it, especially in resource-constrained, single-node environments.&#xA;What Does “Yellow” Mean? In Elasticsearch:&#xA;green: All primary and replica shards are assigned and active. yellow: All primary shards are active, but at least one replica shard is unassigned. red: At least one primary shard is missing → critical! Why Yellow Happens on Single Nodes In single-node clusters, Elasticsearch cannot assign replica shards (because replicas must be on a different node). So any index with replicas will always be yellow unless:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rescue to the softraid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rescuetotheraid/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rescuetotheraid/index.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction So I had this USB Disk attached to my OpenBSD Router used as storage, one saturday when I was walking by I noticed the weird clicking sounds from the disk. So I knew my time was running before the disc would fail.&#xA;Curiously, when I plugged the same drive into a Linux box, it was detected — and even showed a valid OpenBSD partition table. That gave me a glimmer of hope: maybe the hardware wasn’t completely dead yet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putting my gpg key on my yubikey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gpgonmyyubi/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gpgonmyyubi/index.html</guid>
      <description>Why GPG? In an age where digital identities are easily faked and impersonation is just a few clicks away, I decided to take a step forward in securing mine. GPG (GNU Privacy Guard) provides a robust way to authenticate, encrypt, and sign digital content. In this post, I’ll walk you through how I:&#xA;Created a GPG key pair Set up subkeys and stored them on my YubiKey Published my public key on my website Signed and encrypted personal documents for secure public sharing Configured email signing using GPG Step 1: Installing GPG To start, I made sure GPG was installed. Here’s how I did it on each of my systems:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>