<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forensicwheels - Tag - Forensic wheels</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/forensicwheels/index.html</link>
    <description></description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:24:04 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/forensicwheels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 16:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/index.html</guid>
      <description>Short intro about myself</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open BSD and Zen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/openbsdzen/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 12:48:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/openbsdzen/index.html</guid>
      <description>About As someone who is passionate about security and has an interest in Unix operating systems, OpenBSD particularly captivates due to its dedication to security, stability, and simplicity. In comparison to other OSes, what sets OpenBSD apart? And how do these principles align with my journey through Zen meditation?&#xA;At first glance, OpenBSD and Zen may appear to be vastly disparate concepts - one being a potent operating system, while the other is a spiritual practice originating from ancient China. However, as I delved deeper into both realms, I uncovered some fascinating similarities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The unseen hero of OpenBSD, talking about OpenBSD&#39;s malloc</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/openbsdmalloc/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:51:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/openbsdmalloc/index.html</guid>
      <description>The unseen hero of OpenBSD: talking about OpenBSD’s malloc Introduction When people talk about operating system security, they often mention firewalls, cryptography, or privilege separation. But one of the most important security components usually remains invisible: the memory allocator. On OpenBSD, the default allocator—malloc—is not just an implementation detail. It reflects the project’s long-standing commitment to robustness and safety. This article explains, at a high level, why OpenBSD’s malloc is so unusual, so protective, and so “unseen yet essential”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SANS FOR608</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sans_for608/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 16:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sans_for608/index.html</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Threat hunting and Response (FOR608) Introduction Brief overview of forensic analysis and its application Course Overview/ Preparing your Index Proactive Detection and Response (608.1) Scaling Response and Analysis (608.2) Modern Attacks against Windows and Linux FIR (608.3) Analyzing macOS and Docker Containers (608.4) Cloud Attacks and Response (608.5) Capstone: Enterprise-Class IR Challenge Key Takeaways Summary of key concepts and skills learned during the course learning outcomes and their application in real-world scenarios Conclusion and Recommendations Summary of overall effectiveness of the SANS Forensics course for608 Recommendations for future students looking to learn forensic analysis skills Enterprise Threat hunting and Response (FOR608) Course description from SANS 1 :</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to monitor systems with monit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/monitmon/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 11:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/monitmon/index.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction Requirements Installing Monit on OpenBSD Monit – Essential System and Router Services System monitoring runs every 45 seconds. The first check is delayed by 120 seconds to avoid overloading the system immediately after boot.&#xA;set daemon 45 with start delay 120 Monit logs to syslog. `idfile` and `statefile` store Monit’s persistent state and identity across restarts.&#xA;set log syslog set idfile /var/monit/id set statefile /var/monit/state Limits control buffer sizes and timeouts for program outputs, network I/O, and service start/stop/restart operations. This prevents Monit from hanging or processing excessive data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Yellow Shards in Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/yellowshardsinelastic/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/yellowshardsinelastic/index.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction If you’re running Elasticsearch on a single node — like a Raspberry Pi or small lab setup like I am — you might notice some indices appear with a yellow health status.&#xA;This show article explains what that means and how to fix it, especially in resource-constrained, single-node environments.&#xA;What Does “Yellow” Mean? In Elasticsearch:&#xA;green: All primary and replica shards are assigned and active. yellow: All primary shards are active, but at least one replica shard is unassigned. red: At least one primary shard is missing → critical! Why Yellow Happens on Single Nodes In single-node clusters, Elasticsearch cannot assign replica shards (because replicas must be on a different node). So any index with replicas will always be yellow unless:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putting my gpg key on my yubikey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gpgonmyyubi/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gpgonmyyubi/index.html</guid>
      <description>Why GPG? In an age where digital identities are easily faked and impersonation is just a few clicks away, I decided to take a step forward in securing mine. GPG (GNU Privacy Guard) provides a robust way to authenticate, encrypt, and sign digital content. In this post, I’ll walk you through how I:&#xA;Created a GPG key pair Set up subkeys and stored them on my YubiKey Published my public key on my website Signed and encrypted personal documents for secure public sharing Configured email signing using GPG Step 1: Installing GPG To start, I made sure GPG was installed. Here’s how I did it on each of my systems:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rescue to the softraid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rescuetotheraid/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:03:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rescuetotheraid/index.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction So I had this USB Disk attached to my OpenBSD Router used as storage, one saturday when I was walking by I noticed the weird clicking sounds from the disk. So I knew my time was running before the disc would fail.&#xA;Curiously, when I plugged the same drive into a Linux box, it was detected and even showed a valid OpenBSD partition table. That gave me a glimmer of hope: maybe the hardware wasn’t completely dead yet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forensic Wheels</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/all-posts/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:48:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/all-posts/index.html</guid>
      <description>DRAFT My travel and stay at buddhas weg @personal DRAFT Collecting netflow data with pflow(1) and logstash @threathuntingopenbsdvisibility DRAFT Joe Weitzenbaum forever Warum weitzenbaum heute wichtiger ist als emails zuvor Josef Weizenbaum – approximiert, aus dem Nebel der Bedeutung</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>